Morgan Collado

Austin, TX 78753 | 781-724-5310 | morgan.collado@gmail.com Github morgancollado | https://www.linkedin.com/in/morgancollado

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack developer with 2 years of production experience. With a background in training, organizational development, possesses a keen eye for streamlining front-end and back-end processes using Ruby on Rails and React. Collaborative team player who empowers and motivates co-workers to be their best.

SKILLS

NextJS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, Git, HTML, CSS, CI/CD, AWS, Docker, Bilingual in Spanish **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

MyFitnessPal

A NextJS application that is supported by a Rails backend.

- Leverages react-query for state management
- Used Material UI to create custom reusable components that are mobile first
- Updated pages on myfitnesspal.com to ensure accessibility best practices were followed

Customer Relationship Management Tool

Internal utility used by the MyFitnessPal employees to manage coupons, subscriptions and user accounts.

- Helped reduce the footprint of Redux replacing it with react-query
- Extended the coupon creation service to accept a dynamic SKU enabling product to have more control over the coupons they create

MvFitnessPal Backend

A legacy Ruby on Rails app that supports MyFitnessPal's web and mobile clients

- Wrote CRUD APIs for several fields of the user model to support the migration of legacy rails views to our modern NextJS app
- Researched and resolved security vulnerabilities

North Texas Abortion Support Network App - Github | Demo

A React front end supported by a Rails API backend that allows clients to request rides to their appointments

- Utilized Redux to manage state across the application so that presentational components are reusable
- Incorporated Material UI to create an interface that is intuitive and easy to use
- Employed thunk to create async calls to the backend which was configured to use sessions to keep a user logged in

EXPERIENCE

MyFitnessPal Austin, TX Software Engineer I, Web April 2021 - Feb 2023

- Migrated legacy frontend code base spread across three repositories into a single NextJS app
- Developed an onboarding flow for web that resulted in a 80% increase of sign ups
- Enabled increased product flexibility by working on internal tools

TaskRabbit Austin, TX

Technical Support Specialist - Spanish

Oct 2019 - March 2021

- Collaborate cross functionally with Engineering and Product depts to identify and resolve complex technical issues
- Understand the platform at a deep level to provide an excellent support experience for every customer

Austin Energy Austin, TX

Training and Development Specialist

July 2018 - August 2019

Developed and facilitated trainings for the Utility Contact Center and Austin 311

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Austin, TX March, 2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Boston, MA

Northeastern University

Bachelor of Science in Philosophy

May, 2012